import './App.css'

import { Box } from '@mui/material'
import { useEffect, useState } from 'react'
import { Manager } from 'socket.io-client'
import ClickCard from './ClickCard'
import FinalCard from './FinalCard'
import IntoCard from './IntroCard'
import QACard from './QACard'

let socket: any = null
const questions = [
  { question: 'At which company has Akhil spent most of his professional life?', answer: 'vmWare' },
  { question: "You should wish a very Happy Birthday today to which of Akhil's friends?", answer: 'madHav' },
  { question: "Find any of Akhil's friends or family members who went to Georgia Tech and ask them to complete this phrase: To hell withâ€¦?", answer: 'gEorgia' },
  { question: "Akhil's friend Anand developed this devious but brilliant game! Anand started his career at which popular AI chip company?", answer: 'Nvidia' },
  { question: "Akhil's cousins come in all ages! Who is the eldest cousin here today? Hint: Ask for Titoo", answer: 'rIshi' },
  { question: `Now go find the youngest cousin! What's her name?`, answer: 'Shivani' },
  { question: 'Priya, Vishu, Nikhil, and Akhil once missed a train trying to get to which PNW city?', answer: 'portlaNd' },
  { question: 'Gunan was a recent contestant on which popular TV game show?', answer: 'jEopardy' },
  { question: "What is Amu's real name?", answer: 'miHir' },
  { question: 'What is the first name of the comedian that Neha and Akhil watched on their first date?', answer: 'hAsan' },
  { question: 'Where in Montana did Akhil coach soccer?', answer: 'misSoula' },
  { question: 'Lesly, Akhil, and Amu once camped outside to save money while attending the world cup in which country?', answer: 'Brazil' },
  { question: "Which 'corner' Colorado city is Maddie from?", answer: 'Durango' },
  { question: 'Akhil has 3 friends with the same name. What is their name? Hint: they are all Ismaili', answer: 'Ali' },
  { question: "What is Tina's profession?", answer: 'lawYer' },
]
const isLocal = window.location.hostname.includes('localhost')
const port = isLocal ? '4001' : '443'
const backendUrl = `${window.location.protocol}//${window.location.hostname}:${port}`

console.log(backendUrl)
function App() {
  const [answers, setAnswers] = useState<Record<string, string>>({})
  const [clickDone, setClickDone] = useState(false)
  const [clickEnabled, setClickEnabled] = useState(false)
  useEffect(() => {
    // const manager = new Manager(`${window.location.hostname}:4001`)
    const manager = new Manager(backendUrl)
    socket = manager.socket('/') // main namespace
    manager.on('reconnect', () => {
      console.log('reconnected')
      setClickEnabled(true)
    })
    manager.on('reconnect_error', () => {
      console.log('reconnect_error')
      setClickEnabled(false)
    })
    manager.on('reconnect_failed', () => {
      console.log('reconnect_failed')
      setClickEnabled(false)
    })
    function solve() {
      setClickDone(true)
      setAnswers(
        questions.reduce(
          (p, c) => {
            p[c.question] = c.answer
            return p
          },
          {
            click: 100000,
          } as Record<string, any>
        )
      )
    }
    socket.on('solve', solve)

    socket.on('completed', (e: Record<string, string>) => {
      setClickEnabled(true)
      console.log('completed', e)

      if (e.from !== socket.id) {
        if (!e.click || answers.click > e.click) {
          e.click = answers.click
        }
        return setAnswers({
          ...answers,
          ...e,
        })
      }
    })

    socket.on('init', (e: Record<string, string>) => {
      if (e.solved) return solve()
      setClickEnabled(true)
      console.log('init', e)
      if (e) {
        return setAnswers({
          ...answers,
          ...e,
        })
      }
    })
    return () => {
      socket.disconnect()
    }
  }, [])

  const isSolved = (!clickEnabled || clickDone) && Object.keys(answers).length >= questions.length + 1 // +1 for click
  return (
    <Box sx={{ width: '100vw', height: '100vh', overflow: 'scroll' }}>
      <IntoCard />
      {questions.map(({ question, answer }) => {
        return (
          <QACard
            key={question}
            question={question}
            answer={answer}
            initRes={answers[question]}
            onFinish={(a) => {
              console.log('onFinish')
              setAnswers({
                ...answers,
                [question]: a,
              })
              console.log('emitting')
              socket.emit('complete', {
                from: socket.id,
                question,
                answer: a,
              })
              console.log('emitted')
            }}
          />
        )
      })}
      <ClickCard
        // @ts-ignore
        otherCount={answers.click || 0}
        onFinish={() => setClickDone(true)}
        onClick={() => {
          socket.emit('click', {
            from: socket.id,
          })
        }}
      />
      {isSolved ? <FinalCard /> : null}
    </Box>
  )
}

export default App
